来吧  带你看看我的地盘
Come on. Let me show you my place, huh?
我得发到微薄上
Oh! I gotta tweet this.
谁都不会相信我竟然和...
No one will believe I'm with...
美味尼克在一起
the Terrific Nick.
我是"正宗"尼克
Mm. Uh, "Authentic" Nick.
别叫成"美味"
Not "Terrific", Okay?
我是说...我们才是最棒的
I mean, uh... we're the best.
当然了
I'll bet.
闻起来真香
And it smells so good.
确实...挺香
It does... smell good.
有人在吗
Somebody here?
老爸
Dad?
像烤排骨  是烤肉披萨吗
It smells like ribs. Is that barbecue pizza?
我们不做烤肉披萨
No, we don't do barbecue pizza, all right?
好味尼克那种冒牌店才做
That's for the hacks like Terrific Nick.
脆脆的
Ooh, nice and crispy.
你最爱吃了
Just the way you like it.
你吃吧  我不饿
You eat it. I'm not hungry.
你可从来不拒绝火鸡培根
You've never said no to turkey bacon.
怎么了
What's wrong?
-没事  -肯定有事
- Nothing. - Something.
别逼我钳你
Don't make me tong you.
笑都不笑  看来很严重
Not even a smile. Must be serious.
是劳伦的生日派对  我不去了
It's Lauren's birthday party. I'm not going.
什么  你这几周一直在说
What? You been talking about that party for weeks.
"肯定是本世纪最棒的派对"
"It's gonna be the party of the century."
昨天劳伦找到我
Yesterday Lauren came up to me,
当着所有人的面撤回了对我的邀请
and in front of everybody, told me I was disinvited.
太丢脸了
It was humiliating.
劳伦为什么这么做
Why would Lauren do something like that?
她可是你最好的朋友
She's one of your best friends.
她曾经是
She was one of my best friends.
我也不知道她为什么要那么做
I have no idea why she's acting like this,
她拒绝跟我谈  阿什利和其他人
And she refuses to talk to me, and Ashley's still invited,
都还在被邀请之列
and so is everyone else.
就好像我是社交怪胎一样
And it's like I'm a social leper.
你不去阿什利也不会去的
Well, Ashley's not gonna go without you.
不能因为我被孤立而连累他
Just because I have leprosy doesn't mean he should.
我觉得你该开一个派对跟她叫板
Well, I think you should throw a rival party
把你的朋友都邀请来
and invite all your friends to that one instead.
她今晚举行派对  还有乐队现场演奏
The party's tonight, and she has a live band performing.
我比不上她的
I can't compete with that.
那我给劳伦妈妈打电话  我...
Well, then I'll call Lauren's mom, and I'll--
你开玩笑吧
You're joking, right?
那我就成了被孤立的告密者了
What, so I can be a leper and a tattletale?
我17岁了  我自己能处理好
I'm 17. I can deal with this on my own.
只是...我的每一丝直觉
It's just... every instinct in my body
都在暗示我  我得保护她
is telling me to protect her.
我明白  不过涉及到青少年的事
Yeah, but when it comes to teenagers,
连你的保护不了她  再说阿丽克西斯
not even you can protect her. Alexis is gonna have to deal
终生都要与小人打交道
with backstabbers her whole life.
她很聪明  完全能解决好
But she's intelligent enough to rise above all of that.
我说不准  她看上去已经准备好要杀人了
I don't know. She looked like she was ready to commit murder.
说起谋杀
Speaking of murder.
我以为东边的好味尼克披萨店才是一流的
I thought Terrific Nick's on the east side was number one.
不  那家叫正宗好味尼克披萨店
Uh, no, that's Authentic Terrific Nick's.
-这家只叫正宗尼克  -这里不是好味
- This is just Authentic Nick's. - This isn't Terrific?
只是正宗而已  这也不是好味正宗尼克披萨店
No, just Authentic. It's also not Terrific Authentic Nick's,
-对面才是  -到底有什么差别
- But that's across the street. - What's the difference?
差别在于这家的烤箱烤尸体
The difference is, this one has a dead body in the oven.
好...吧
O-kay.
-这可真是...  -烤得挺好
- That is really... - Well-done.
再过几个小时也许能烤好
Another couple of hours, maybe,
不过我还挺走运  他只是半熟
but luckily for me, he's only half-baked.
男性  四十多岁  我只能判断出这些
Male, mid-40s, that's about as much I.D. as I can give you.
根据烤箱设置和尸体内部温度
Based on the oven setting and the body's core temperature,
我推断他凌晨两点就被放进去了
I'd say he went in no sooner than 2:00 a.m.
我有点不敢问  死因是...
I'm afraid to ask. Cause of death?
不是烤死的  胸口穿透性刺伤
It wasn't the oven. The stab wound through the chest
表明他被放入时已经死亡
says he was dead when he went in.
没有强行闯入的痕迹
No sign of forced entry.
不过我们还是在检测门把手上的指纹
But we're running the prints on the door handle just the same.
好的  烤箱上的也检测下
All right. Run 'em on the oven as well.
-谁发现的  -小尼克
- Who found him? - Uh, Nick Jr.
正宗家的  不是好味家的
Authentic, not Terrific.
不  我不知道他是谁
No. I got no idea who he is.
我打开烤箱  他就在里面了
I mean, I open up the oven, and bam--there he is.
昨晚最后待在这里的是谁
And who were the last ones here last night?
我爸和我
My dad and me.
我们11点左右打烊
We closed around 11:00,
然后我去了凯达吧
And then I hit up the Kaydar Lounge,
遇上一位女士  我们就一起回到这儿
met up with a lady friend, and then we came back here
想..."尝片儿披萨"
to, uh... have a slice.
那是几点
And when was that?
不确定  4点半吧
I don't know. 4:30.
那位女士在哪儿
Where's your lady friend now?
她吐个不停
She was kinda throwing up a lot,
医护人员就把她带走了
so the paramedics had to take her in.
不过我有她号码
Oh, but I kept her number.
我觉得你们不会再碰面了
I-I don't think there's gonna be a second date.
-也对  -抱歉
- Yeah, you're right. - I'm sorry.
我需要你提供一份雇员和送餐人员的
I'm gonna need a list of all of your employees
-详细名单  -你该不会
- and delivery staff. - You don't
觉得烤箱里是我们的伙计吧
think it was one of our guys in the oven, do you?
等你给我名单  我就开始致电询问
As soon as you get me that list, I'll start making phone calls.
我简直不能相信
Ohh. I don't believe this.
肯定是开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
老爸  这些人是警察
Dad, these are the cops.
你肯定是正宗尼克
You must be Authentic Nick.
-独一无二  -尼克
- The one and only. - Nick?
名单上业主叫拉尔夫·卡波
I have the proprietor listed as Ralph Carbone.
就是我  人人都叫我尼克
Yeah, that's me. Everybody calls me Nick.
为什么
Why?
因为人人都那么叫我
Because that's what everybody calls me.
真不敢相信那群混球在烤箱里放了具尸体
I can't believe those bastards put a body in my oven.
很遗憾  卡波先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Carbone.
-你知道是谁干的吗  -当然
- You think that you know who did this? - Yeah, sure.
我打赌就是那个混球
I'll bet it was that Jackhole.
美味正宗尼克
Terrific Authentic Nick?
萨尔·马拉沃塔  他以前给我们干
Sal Malavolta. He used to work for us years ago before opening
后来在街对面开了他自己的破披萨店
his own lousy pizza shop right across the street.
他偷了我的秘方
He stole my friggin' recipes.
肯定是萨尔和另外两个人干的
It's Sal that done this, along with the other two.
另外俩人是谁
The other two?
-那边那个恶棍  -美味尼克
- Yeah, that vulture there. - Terrific Nick?
他叫维尼·德尔菲诺  还有那边那个二货
Vinnie Delfino. And that dirtbag there.
-正宗好味尼克  -他叫卢卡·萨巴里尼
- And Authentic Terrific Nick. - Luca Sabalini.
他们三个都是小偷
All three of them, they're thieves.
他们利用我们的名气  他们都不是真正的尼克
They live off our name, and they're not even real Nicks.
-我才是真尼克  -可你真名叫拉尔夫
- I'm the only real Nick. - And your real name is Ralph.
一点没错  这些年来他们一直想让我倒闭
Exactly. They been trying to run me outta dodge for years.
现在又做出这等事  还有谁会买我家的披萨
And now this. Who's gonna buy my pizza now, huh?
喂  喂  你高兴了吧  我开不了张了
Hey! Hey! You happy? I'm outta business!
卡波先生  你为什么认为
Mr. Carbone, what makes you think
这是他们中某人干的
that one of them did this?
几个星期前  他们其中一个
A few weeks ago, one of them
偷偷放了一加仑肥皂到我的秘制酱里
snuck a gallon of soap into my secret sauce.
导致我那天卖的披萨都被退回来了
Cost me a whole day of returned pies.
听着  我或许报复过  或许没有
Now look, uh, I may or may not have retaliated,
假设说我报复了
but if I did,
他们把一具死尸放在我的烤箱里
them putting a cadaver in my oven
那不就是  他们反报复吗
that's, uh, them retaliating back.
卡波先生  那不是一具死尸
Mr. Carbone, that's not a cadaver.
什么意思  那是  他们从
What do you mean? It's a--they brought--
他们从医学院搞来的
they--they got this from some medical school.
不  这不是恶作剧  是谋杀案
No, this isn't a prank. This is murder.
我们核查了所有员工
We got through to all their employees.
-都活着  -蕾妮
- Everybody's accounted for.  - Lanie,
有没有可能弄清死者身份
what are the chances of getting an I.D.?
根据指纹判断我看没戏  也许要等
I'm not hopeful on fingerprints. We may have to wait
失踪人口报告
for a missing persons report
-和牙科记录  -我们正在挨家排查
- and dental records.  - We also started a canvass
看有没有人昨晚看到了什么
to see if anybody saw anything last night.
好  我们找所有员工录口供
All right, let's get statements off all the employees,
尤其是那些有钥匙的人
especially the ones with keys.
看他们昨晚在做什么
I'd like to know what they were doing last night.
不需要调查一下其他几个披萨店吗
Shouldn't we look into the other Nick's, too?
拜托  老兄  你不会真以为
Come on, bro. You don't really think
这是披萨店之间的竞争导致的吧
this is about some kind of pizza rivalry, do you?
竞争纽约第一的位子  肯定是拼得头破血流啊
Competition to be the best in New York, clear animosity?
卡波说他们之前就闯进来过
Carbone said they'd broken in before.
如果要调查所有能进入这里的人
If we are looking into everyone with access,
他们就不该被排除在外
we should look into them as well.
他说的对
He's right, you know?
在这里  披萨行内竞争很激烈
Pizza's serious business in this town.
好吧  棒极了  就派你去吧
All right. Great. You talk to them.
等等  我
Wait. Me?
不行  我  饶了我吧
No, I... come on.
你必须承认  用披萨烤箱
You know, you have to admit, a pizza oven--
是个处理尸体极高明的手法
very clever way to get rid of a body.
在《消失在黄昏》里  我让精神病律师助理
In "At Dusk We Die," I had my psychotic paralegal
杀了她的虐待狂老板  把尸体放在陶器窖里
kill her abusive boss and put him in a pottery kiln.
几个小时之后  他就化为灰烬了
He was reduced to ashes in a matter of hours.
当然  你已经知道这个情节了  是吧
Of course, you already know this, don't you?
或许凶手正是这么打算的
That's probably what our killer planned on doing
-直到小尼克出现  -我没听错吧
- until Nick Jr. showed up.  - Did I hear right?
你们在美味尼克披萨店的烤箱里发现了一具尸体
You found a body in the oven at Terrific Nick's?
-正宗尼克披萨店  -正宗尼克披萨店
- Authentic Nick's.  - Authentic Nick's?
感谢上帝  我老婆很喜欢美味尼克披萨店
Oh, thank God. My wife loves Terrific Nick's.
我可不想告诉她
I didn't have the heart
现在披萨都是尸体口味的
to tell her it now came in full-bodied flavor.
说得好  我喜欢
Oh, I liked it .. I liked it.
我们调查了所有正宗尼克披萨店的员工
So we ran through all of Authentic Nick's employees.
他们都没嫌疑  但我在另几家店
They alibied out, but I did find a bunch of stuff
-找到一些线索  -刑事申诉
- on the other Nick's.  - Criminal complaints?
没错  过去这几年他们反复申诉
Yeah, dozens of them filed back and forth between
几家披萨店之间的所做所为
all the Nick's over the years--
用砖头砸前窗
bricks through front windows,
划破送货车轮胎  燃烧大便
slashed delivery car tires, ooh, flaming bags of poo.
-谢了  -没事
- Thank you. - Yep.
怎么  就这样算啦
What, that's it?
燃烧大便  在秘制酱里放肥皂
Flaming bags of poo, soap in secret sauces?
拜托  卡塞尔  难道你觉得
Come on, Castle. What do you think,
这些家伙突然间就从
these guys suddenly graduated
对手间的恶作剧升级为谋杀了吗
from frat pranks to murder?
如我所料
As expected,
尸体已经严重烧焦  无法找到指纹
the body was too badly burned to get any prints,
但我发现了这个
But I did find this.
看到了吧  这里原本应该是胫骨
You see here where the shin bone should be?
那些是钛板
Those are titanium plates.
半机械人杀手从未来被派到这里
So killer cyborg sent from the future,
反抗军截取了他的坐标
resistance fighters intercept his coordinates,
将他传送进了披萨烤箱  拯救了人类
redirect him into a pizza oven, saving humanity.
这些钛板有序列号
The plates have serial numbers.
我在手术数据库搜索了一下
I ran 'em through the surgical database
找到了匹配的人
And got an I.D.
格顿·伯恩斯
Gordon Burns.
Gordon Burns?
是的  卡塞尔  伯恩斯[有燃烧的意思]
Yes, Castle, Burns.
说吧  想开玩笑就开  不必客气
Go ahead, make your joke. Get it out of your system.
格顿·伯恩斯  《纽约记事报》的那个
Gordon Burns, as in "New York Ledger"?
-你认识他  -没有私交  他是个记者
- You know him? - Well, not personally. He was a reporter.
我以前很喜欢他的文章
I used to love his work.
尸体上还有没有别的东西
Did you find anything else on the body?
一个融掉了的手机夹  但没有手机
A melted cell phone belt clip, but there was no cell phone.
犯罪现场也没有
Yeah, it wasn't at the crime scene, either.
那是他的钱包
And that's his wallet.
几张信用卡
Some credit cards,
驾照  都化掉了
driver's license-- that's all melted.
女朋友  还是妻子
Girlfriend, wife?
据记录伯恩斯离婚了  没有其他亲属
Burns is listed as divorced, no next of kin.
他是个战地记者  调查记者
He was a war correspondent, an investigative reporter.
怎么会被塞进了披萨烤箱呢
What was he doing in a pizza oven?
也许他的编辑知道
Maybe his editor knows.
我们是朋友  所以当我升任报纸编辑之后
We were friends, so when I became editor of the paper,
-我首先雇的就是他  -他写的那些故事
- he was my first hire.  - The kinds of stories he wrote,
一定得罪了不少人
he must have stepped on his fair share of toes.
这几年没有  他已经退出那个圈子好久了
Not for years. He'd been out of the game for a while.
为什么
Why is that?
他的孩子在一次车祸中去世了
His kid was killed in an accident.
她才十岁  那之后  他开始酗酒
She was 10. After that, he finally gave in
不能自拔
to his love affair with the bottle.
我们看到他仍在你们的员工名单之列
We see that you still had him on the payroll.
他不时为生活版块
He did the occasional human interest story
写一些关于民生的报道
for our lifestyles section.
有点浪费他的才能  但能支付他的租金
A waste of his talent, but it let him make rent,
续交保险
keep his insurance.
肖恩先生  他最近有在忙些什么吗
Mr. Shaw, was he working on anything recently?
就是上周我分配给他的一篇稿子
Just a puff piece I had assigned him last week.
关于什么的
About what?
披萨之战
The pizza wars.
那些正宗啊  绝妙啊
You know, those Authentic, Amazing,
美味披萨店主经常为谁最好而争吵
Terrific guys always fighting over which one's the best.
这里不是阿富汗  但格顿还是格顿
It wasn't Afghanistan. But Gordon was Gordon.
几天前他给我打了电话  说事态比我想象的
He called a few days ago and said it was much bigger
-有深度  -怎么个有深度
- than I thought.  - Bigger how?
他没说  但那是披萨之战
He didn't say, but I mean, it's pizza wars.
-能闹多大  -大到不惜杀人灭口
- How big could it be?  - Big enough to kill for.
翻译：咖啡十三   旺仔爱旺妹   媛媛   深深   落末一地   LyraL   思无邪   irene430
时间轴：Jimmybeck   糖泡泡   好油油    校对：大卫熊   后期&总监：瓜瓜
我们要更深入的调查所有的尼克披萨店
Let's dig deeper into all of the Nick's--
美味  正宗以及其它的
Terrific, Authentic, and otherwise,
还要对他们所有的员工做背景调查
and let's also run bagrground checks on all their employees.
你知道吗  他去过阿富汗
You know, this guy survived Afghanistan,
报道过伊拉克战争  甚至在天安门广场也报道过
the invasion of Araq, even Tian'anmen Square,
却因为写一篇披萨的报道而被杀
to be killed doing a puff piece on pizza?
这就像做警察一样  兄弟
It's like being a cop, bro.
你在和一群武装帮派的火拼中幸免
You survive a firefight with a dozen armed gangbangers
结果却被车撞死了或是在长岛高速上开超速罚单
only to be hit by a car or write a speed ticket on the LIE.
我追踪了伯恩斯那失踪的手机
I ran a trace on Burns' missing phone.
它要么是没电  要么就是关机了
It's either out of battery or turned off.
好  查一下他的通话记录和消费记录
All right, run LUDs and financials.
我要知晓他昨晚在哪里  在做什么
I want to find out where he was and what he was doing last night.
这就去
On it.
这案子肯定是关于
This has to be about
某个比谁的披萨最好更重要的事
something bigger than who has the best pizza.
伯恩斯可能把他写的报道的笔记
You know, Burns probably had notes
和草稿放在了他的公寓里
and drafts of his story in his apartment.
如果我们找到了它们  我们就能
If we can find them, we can figure out
-查出昨晚他在忙些什么  -我们出发吧
- what he was up to last night. - Let's go.
门曾被踹开过
Door's been kicked open.
屋里没人
Room's clear.
这地方被翻得乱七八糟
This place is trashed.
我去问问邻居
I'm gonna check with the neighbors,
-看看有没有人听到什么动静  -好的
- see if anybody heard anything. - Okay.
这些抽屉都掏空了
These drawers have been emptied.
如果这里曾经装着文件或是笔记
If there were files or notes,
现在它们全被拿走了
they're gone now.
不管他在报道什么
Well, whatever he was working on,
有人不希望我们找到它
someone didn't want us to find it.
你还好吗
You okay?
嗯  不
Yeah. No, yeah.
我觉得我以前见过她
Um, I think I met her.
我去参加他的图书签售会的时候  那本
I went to a book signing of his, the one he did on the, uh,
关于萨拉热窝狙击手的书
Sarajevo Snipers.
她...
She was...
他签售的时候她就在旁边
coloring next to him while he was signing books.
他肯定是个不错的作家  能让你屈尊排队
He must have been a good writer for you to stand in line.
没错  他的确是
Yeah. He was.
走吧  我们叫鉴证组过来
Come on. Let's go get C.S.U.
我发现了一些奇怪的事
Hey. I got something weird.
伯恩斯的邻居  她说她从上周起替他
Burns' neighbor, she says she's been holding
接收他的信件  显然伯恩斯告诉她
his mail for the last week. Apparently Burns told her
他要出国一段时间
he was going out of the country for a while.
出国吗  我们知道他一直在这儿
Out of the country? We know he's been here.
当你不希望别人找你时
You know, that's the kind of lie that you tell people
你就会撒这种谎
when you don't want anyone looking for you.
如果他在别的地方待过
And if he's been staying somewhere else,
我们还有找到他的笔记的可能
there's a chance we could still find his notes.
我联系一下他的主编
I'm gonna to get ahold of his editor,
看看他知不知道他可能在哪待过
find out where he might have been staying.
一篇关于披萨的报道怎么会让人东躲西藏
How does a story about pizza send somebody into hiding?
或导致他被杀  贝克特
Or get them killed? Beckett.
刚刚拿到鉴证组的报告
Hey. Just got the C.S.U. report back.
披萨店后门把手被擦得很干净
The back doorknob of the pizza shop was wiped clean,
但他们发现披萨烤箱上布满了尼克的指纹
but they did find Nick's prints all over the pizza oven.
这可以预料到  他在那儿工作
Well, that's to be expected. I mean, he worked there.
不是正宗尼克的指纹   这些指纹
Not Authentic Nick. These prints belong to
是他街对面的邻居
his neighbor across the street--
美味正宗尼克的
Terrific Authentic Nick.
尼克  或者我该称你为萨尔
so, Nick, or should I say Sal?
-认识这个人吗  -是的  我认识他
- Know this guy? - Yeah, I know him.
是那个报道我们的故事的记者
That's the reporter doing the story on us.
你们两个都谈了什么
And what did the two of you talk about?
谁是真正的尼克
Who's the real Nick,
我跟他说了我祖父尼克
and I told him about my grandpa Nick
说他是地道的埃利斯岛移民
and how he was an authentic Ellis Island immigrant
他搬来莫特街的第一天起
who was flipping his terrific dough
就开始做美味的比萨了
on Mott Street the very day he arrived.
还说了什么
What else?
就这些了  为什么这么问
That's it. Why?
只是觉得这算不上什么杀人的理由
Just doesn't seem like a good enough reason to kill.
杀人
Kill?
萨尔  我们发现烤箱上沾满了你的指纹
We found your fingerprints, sal, all over the oven.
你们发现了我的指纹
You found my prints?
是的
Yeah.
我们为何不从头说起
So why don't we back up?
你告诉我们为什么要杀了伯恩斯
And you tell us why you killed Burns.
-这次你别加那么多"芝士"  -我能解释
- And this time, hold the extra cheese. - I-I can explain.
我的确去过那儿  但我没杀任何人
I was there, but I didn't kill nobody.
拉尔夫以为我往他的酱汁里放了肥皂
Ralph thought I was soaping his sauce,
所以他闯入我的店里
so he broke into my place
把我电路板上的所有断路器都拿走了
and took all the breakers out of my electrical panel.
他总是炫耀他的烤箱如何高级
Now he's always bragging about his oven,
所以我想
so I thought I'd--
放一具尸体在里面
Put a body in it.
不  是把它偷走
No, steal it.
我几天前夜里去了他那儿
I went over there a couple nights ago
看看我需要什么才能把它偷出来
to see what I need to get it out.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding me, right?
我昨晚在史丹顿岛区的奥马利酒吧
I was in O'Meary's on Staten Island last night,
一直待到打烊
till closing.
那晚是飞镖之夜  我得了第三名
Okay? It was dart night. I took third place.
你想要调查  那就去调查拉尔夫吧
You want to look at somebody, look at Ralph.
为什么查拉尔夫
Why ralph?
你以为他靠卖那些难吃的披萨赚钱吗
What do you think, he makes that money with his crappy pizza?
他手脚不干净  那才是我离开的原因
He's connected. That's why I left.
他一心想着为他的朋友洗钱
All he cares about is laundering money for his wise guy pals.
你不会碰巧跟伯恩斯提过这事儿吧
You didn't happen to mention this to Burns, did you?
事实上  我提过
As a matter of fact, I did.
洗钱吗
Money laundering? Whoa.
我们在联邦资料库里查过你
We ran you through the federal database.
我们知道联邦调查局在90年代的调查
We know about the FBI investigation in the '90s
还有你与斯伯拉诺犯罪家族的关系
and about your connection to the Spolano crime family.
和我的关系
My connection?
他是我隔代的二表亲
He's my second cousin once removed.
我每过五年会在感恩节和他见上一面
I see him at Thanksgiving once every five years.
联邦调查局什么也没查出来
And the feds never found anything.
他们的确没查出来
The feds didn't,
但也许伯恩斯查出来了
but maybe burns did.
到底发生了什么  拉尔夫
So what happened, Ralph?
他威胁要揭发你吗
Did he threaten to expose you?
你本打算让他消失
You make him... disappear until your--
直到你儿子
your kid showed up
在那令你自豪的烤箱完成任务前出现了
before that oven you're so proud of could finish the job?
我靠卖披萨赚钱
I make money with my pizza.
你想要查我的账簿吗  那就查吧
You want to look at my books? Go ahead.
你们会和联邦调查局查到的一样
You're gonna find exactly the same thing the feds found--
什么-也-没有
nada, zip, zilch.
萨尔让你们俩来调查我的  是吗
Sal put yous two up to this, right?
之前就是萨尔让联邦调查局
Sal's the one brought the feds in
来调查我的  想让我关门大吉
in the first place, trying to shut me down.
你们应该调查一下他
You should be looking at him.
萨尔昨晚有不在现场证明
Sal had an alibi for last night.
你有吗  卡波先生
What about you, Mr. Carbone?
我在家躺在床上  你可以问我老婆
I'm at home in bed. You could ask my wife.
那个记者  问我的都是关于披萨的事情
And that reporter, all he asked me about was pizza.
那个人肯定犯过什么罪
That guy is guilty of something.
除非我们有证据
Not until we have proof.
莱恩  查到我们的被害人昨晚在哪了吗
Hey, Ryan. Any luck on where our victim was last night?
我们还在等他的银行的信息
Well, we're still waiting for info from his bank,
但我拿到了他的电话单  昨晚没有通话
but I got his luds. Nothing last night,
只有前几天和他的主编打过
And only a few calls to his editor
-几个电话  -一个正在写报道的记者吗
- in the previous days. - A reporter chasing down a story?
不对  应该会打很多电话的
No, there should be dozens of calls.
也可能他从他住的地方打电话
Well, maybe he was making them from wherever he was staying.
照片上的女孩查出什么线索没
Any leads on the girl in the photo?
没有  我和他在波特兰的前妻联系过
No. But I got in touch with Burns' ex in Portland.
-他们很多年都没见过面了  -重大发现
- They hadn't seen each other in years. - Yo. Pay dirt.
我排查了伯恩斯公寓所在的大楼
I canvassed Burns' building.
一开始全都说
At first, it was all,
"他是个安静的人  他独来独往"
"He's so quiet. He just keeps to himself."
但一个刚刚回家的邻居说
But this other neighbor who just came home
她看到伯恩斯在离开之前
said that she saw Burns and another guy having
和另一个人大吵过一架
a knock-down, drag-out yelling match just before he left.
-关于什么  -她只记得那个人大喊道
- About what? - All she remembers is the other guy yelling,
"你要是敢报道出来  我发誓我会杀了你"
"If you try to print that, I swear to god, I'll kill ya!"
知道那个人的长相了吗
Did you get a description?
我给你个提示  他是正宗的
And I'll give you a hint. He's Authentic...
也是美味的
and Terrific.
我是和伯恩斯吵了一架  那又怎样
So me and Burns argued? So what?
这是个自由的国家
It's a free country.
言论自由可不包括死亡危险  萨巴里尼先生
Free speech doesn't cover death threats, Mr. Sabalini.
-也不包括谋杀  -都说我昨晚在家了
- Or murder. - I told you, I was home last night.
你是这么说的  但你妻子说的不一样
Yeah, you did, but your wife tells us a different story.
她记得在你以为她睡着了之后
It seems she remembers you sneaking out before midnight,
在午夜前偷偷溜了出去
after you thought she was asleep.
她说你是去
She told us you were off to see
"弗拉特布什会那个淫荡的情妇"
"that whore mistress of his over in Flatbush",
早上她质问你这事的时候
and when she confronted you about it this morning,
你说你是进城了
you told her that you went into the city
因为店里的警报响了
because the store alarm was going off.
我们核实了  没响过
We checked. It wasn't.
那么你是对谁撒谎了呢  我还是你妻子
So who were you lying to, Luca, me or your wife?
对我妻子
My wife.
我昨晚跟安琪在一起  你们可以问她
I was with Angie last night. You can ask her.
我会问的  但那不代表我会相信她
I could. But it doesn't mean I'm gonna believe her.
你跟伯恩斯为了什么事争吵
What were you and Burns fighting about?
他要写一些有关我的东西
He was gonna write something about me,
会毁掉我努力经营的一切
destroy everything I've worked for.
-我必须阻止他  -他要写什么
- I had to stop him. - And what was he gonna write?
有关我的披萨
About my pizza.
有关我的无脂披萨为什么这么好吃
About what makes my fat-free pizza taste so good.
我是用真正的奶酪做的
It's made with real cheese.
根本就不是无脂的
There's nothing fat-free about it.
-你为这就说要杀他  -就是表达愤怒
- You were gonna kill for that? - It's an expression.
再说  昨晚伯恩斯给我打电话  说
Besides, Burns called me last night. He said
如果我能帮他一个忙  就不会写出来
he'd consider not running it if I'd do him a favor.
什么忙
What favor?
他没说
Hey, he didn't say what.
他本来说要今天来找我谈的
He was supposed to stop by today to talk about it.
你说他昨晚给你打电话了  从哪打来的
You said that he called you yesterday? From where?
好的  查到了  打到他手机上的电话
Okay, got it. The incoming call on his cell
是从市中心的贝塔酒店打来的
was from the Hotel Beta in midtown.
好的  行动吧
All right, let's go.
谢谢
Thanks.
现金支付  用梅尔维尔的假名入住
Paid in cash, signed in under the name Melville.
这家伙是一心要躲起来啊
This guy's definitely flying under the radar.
卡塞尔  他的电脑在那呢
Castle, there's his computer.
好了
Okay.
"纽约'正宗'和'美味'披萨之战"
"New York's Authentic Terrific pizza wars."
文辞犀利
Sharp narration,
措辞精致
delicate prose.
这不是一篇惊爆内幕
This is not an expose.
-就是一篇推广报道  -都能闻到蒜香了
- It's a puff piece. - Well, I can practically smell the garlic,
但是里面没有
but there's nothing in there
比披萨更重要的事情
that's about anything heavier than pizza.
也没有能招来杀身之祸的
Or what got him killed.
看看他记事本最近记什么了
Mm, his most recent notes.
披萨  食谱
Pizza, recipes,
内...
inter...
怎么了
What?
看啊
Look at that.
那是昨晚
That's last night.
他要见一个人
He was meeting with someone.
就是这个号码的主人  而且就在他死前
Someone from that phone number, just before he was killed.
-我查查  -你还有干这个的软件啊
- I'm gonna run that down. - You have an app for that?
对  纽约警方发布的  才安装上
Yeah, NYPD issue. We just got it.
-我能  -不能
- Can I... - Whoa.
好吧
Fine.
你也别想玩我的"愤怒的小鸟"
Then you don't get to play my "Angry birds",
刚刚出了新款的
and they just came out with a new one.
"强尼·法瑞尔  斯维德·安德森"
"Johnny Farrell, Swede Anderson."
貌似有点印象
How do I know those names?
我没听过  你认出这是谁了吗
I don't know, but recognize this person?
伯恩斯钱包里的照片上那个女人
That's the woman from Burns' wallet.
没错  莫妮卡·怀特
Bingo. Monica Wyatt.
如果她昨晚见过他
And if she met with him last night,
那她可能是最后一个见到活着的伯恩斯的人
she might be the last person to have seen him alive.
你说他们有没有一起吃披萨呢
I wonder if they went out for pizza.
对于卖披萨的来说是不是太高档了
Little upscale for the pizza world.
除非她是中间人
Unless she's a middle man.
洗钱业务的中间人
For the money laundering operation?
她用强尼·法瑞尔和斯维德·安德森的假名
She transfers the assets out of country
把资产过户到国外
into Swiss Bank accounts using the names
存到瑞士银行的账户里
Johnny Farrell and Swede Anderson.
或许她就像她说的那样是个房地产经纪人
Or she's just a real estate agent as she claims to be.
那只是她为了躲避调查局的审查
Oh, that's just her cover to avoid
所用的掩护身份
scrutiny with the Feds.
你小时候  有很多
You had a lot of imaginary
-想象出来的朋友吧  -现在也有啊
- friends growing up, didn't you? - Still do.
你们好  有事吗
Hi. Can I help you?
真不敢相信他还留着这个
I can't believe he still had this.
我们第一次约会的时候他拍了这张照片
He actually took this on our first date.
你们在一起多长时间
And how long were the two of you together?
就几个月
Just a couple of months,
不过那应该是三年前了
but god, this had to be three years ago.
他女儿出事后我们见过几次
I saw him once or twice after his daughter's accident.
他人变了  就好像人还在  魂飞了
He was different. It's like he just drifted away.
你昨晚为什么去见他
What made you see him last night?
我昨晚没见到他
I-I didn't see him last night.
不过他的记事本上写他要在晚上十点见你
Well, according to his notes, he met up with you at 10:00 p.m.
不是见面  是约会
Well, that wasn't a meeting. That was a date.
但是  他没来
But... he didn't show.
你说你们几年没见了
You said you hadn't seen him in years.
那你们怎么又约上会了呢
How did you end up on a date?
我们前些天在街上偶遇
We bumped into each other in the street the other day.
说来巧的出奇
It was weird because...
因为那是在格林威治村  我从不去那里
it was in the village, and I never go down there,
他说他也从不去那里
and he said he doesn't go down there either,
不过他正在写一篇报道
but he was working on a story.
他跟你说是关于什么的报道了吗
Did he tell you what it was about?
没有
No.
他看起来怎么样  焦虑  苦恼
How did he seem... uh, worried, distressed?
他看起来像他自己
He seemed like himself,
像以前的那个他
like his old self,
像是挖掘到了什么内幕一样
like he was on to something.
他刚从记录大厅回来
He'd just come from The Hall of Records,
不知道他找到了什么  反正让他很激动
and whatever he found, he was really excited about.
记录大厅
The Hall of Records?
是的
Yeah.
怀特小姐  强尼·法瑞尔和斯维德·安德森
Ms. Wyatt, do the names Johnny Farrell
这两个名字你听到过吗
or Swede Anderson mean anything to you?
没听过
I can't say they do.
莫妮卡·怀特的话得到证实了
Monica Wyatt... checks.
她的经纪行说她
Her brokerage house says that she complains
总是抱怨佣金太低  很惹人烦
about commissions more than they'd like,
不过除此之外  她没什么不良记录
but other than that, she's clean.
那个记事本上还有别的吗
You find anything else in there?
没有  其他的都是披萨的事了
Nope. The rest is just pizza.
我刚刚查完伯恩斯的财务记录
I just got through Burns' financials.
-昨晚有记录吗  -有  很奇怪
- Any activity last night? - Uh, yeah. Something odd.
晚上11点15分  他用了自动提款机
11:15 p.m., he used his ATM card.
-在哪  -在一个不怎么好的街区
- Where? - A not-so-good neighborhood
离正宗尼克披萨店就15个街区
about 15 blocks away from Authentic Nick's.
但奇怪的是  他都没完成取款
But here's the odd part-- he never finished the transaction.
你是说他取消了取款
You mean he canceled it.
不是  是没完成
No, no, he never finished it.
他插入了银行卡
He popped in his ATM card,
一分钟后  没有操作
but then after about a minute of inactivity,
卡被吞了  就像...
it ate his card. It's almost as if--
发生了什么事
Something happened.
去找自动柜员机的录像  看看怎么回事
Get ATM surveillance. Let's find out what.
我明早去下记录厅
I'm gonna go to the hall of records tomorrow morning
看看能不能发现伯恩斯在忙什么
and see if we can figure out what Burns was up to.
出什么事了
What happened?
阿丽克西斯没听劝阻
Alexis decided to crash Lauren's party,
闯入了劳伦的派对
against our better judgment...
我想
And I take it that
擅闯派对进行得并不顺利
the, uh, party crashing didn't go so well?
如果劳伦不是全世界最无耻的贱人
None of this would've happened if Lauren wasn't
这一切也不会发生
the most conniving bitch in the entire world.
-是有根据的  -乐队表演的时候
- It's warranted. - When the band was performing,
劳伦带着阿什利走上台
Lauren brought Ashley up on stage with her,
而且她当众吻了他
and she kissed him in front of everyone.
-真贱  -她怎么能这么对我和阿什利
- Bitch. - How could she do this to me, to Ashley?
-阿什利有什么反应  -他窘死了
- What did Ashley do? - He was mortified.
他从台上下来  我们就走了
He ran off stage, and we left.
他道了无数次歉
I mean, he was apologizing a thousand times and said
说他压根不知道她会这么做
he had no idea that she was gonna do that.
感觉她这是想拆散我们
It's like she's been trying to break us up this whole time.
这都是她的邪恶计划
It's been her master plan.
亲爱的  可她没成功
Well, she didn't succeed, darling.
你和阿什利的关系比以前更紧密了
You and Ashley are stronger than ever,
而且她让自己看起来像个傻瓜
and-- and she looks like a fool.
我倒希望是这样
Yeah, I wish that were true.
可根据网上的说法  阿什利出轨了
But according to the internet, Ashley cheated on me.
她把他们接吻的照片
She already posted the pictures of them kissing
传到了她的网站上
all over her web site.
真是噩梦一场
It's a nightmare.
贝克特去哪了
Where's Beckett?
记录厅
Oh, hall of records.
-看看伯恩斯在找什么  -那就好
- Tracking down what Burns was looking for. - Great.
听着  如果我给你个网址
Listen... If I gave you a web site,
你能让你技术部的朋友黑进去
could you have your friends at tech hack into it,
再删除点照片吗
and take some pictures down?
又有人上传你的裸照了吗
Did someone find naked pictures of you again?
和我无关  是阿丽克西斯
No, it's not me. It's Alexis.
是为了阿丽克西斯
It's for Alexis.
一只乌鸦刚刚飞过  到底怎么了
Uh, this just got awkward. What's this about?
好吧
Okay.
学校的贱女孩强吻阿丽克西斯的男朋友
Mean girl at school kiss-ambushed Alexis' boyfriend,
又把照片作为证据放到她网站上
and then posted the photographic proof on her web site.
阿丽克西斯  很难过
Alexis... very upset.
我有个朋友叫托尼
I-I could have my friend Tony.
-私底下做这些  -谢了
- Take care of it, you know, off the record. - Thanks.
别告诉贝克特
And, uh, no need to mention this to Beckett.
你知道她对这种事特别在意
You know how she gets with these things.
恩
Yeah.
像为了一己私欲
Things like abusing police resources
而滥用警力资源这种事吗
for your own personal agenda?
你在说什么啊
What?
真搞笑  不是滥用  是  是...
That's ridic-- no, you don't-- ab- -no, that's-- that's...
有什么与披萨店有关的发现吗
So, uh, what'd you find? Anything on Nicks?
不完全是
Uh, not exactly.
伯恩斯在找有关2003年一个叫
Burns requested files relating to the 2003 murder
赫利·罗梅罗的毒贩子的谋杀案的资料
of a drug trafficker named Harley Romero,
又名花花公子赫利  英俊赫利
A.K.A. Harley Playful, also known as Handsome Harley.
根据照片看来  外号是反话
Judging from those photos, I'm guessing it was ironic.
一个死了八年的人能和披萨有什么关系
What's a guy who's been dead for eight years have to do with pizza?
-莱恩  -在
- Mm. Hey, Ryan. - Yep.
你有查过那几个披萨店主
Did you get a chance to look into all the Nicks
和他们的员工们吗
and their employees?
我在过滤这些报告
Oh, yeah, just going over the reports right now.
-都是些小事  -有关于毒品的指控吗
- Mostly minor stuff. - Any drug charges?
没  没有和毒品有关的
No, nothing about drugs.
罗梅罗  你觉得这是黑手党
Romero? You think maybe it's some kind of
跟正宗尼克披萨店扯上关系了吗
mafia tie-in with Authentic Nick's?
根据记录
According to the file,
披萨店跟任何一个黑帮家庭都没有关系
there's no connection to any of the families.
有人不喜欢他
Someone didn't like him.
这上面说他挨了好多枪子
It says here he was shot a dozen times,
被扔进一个油桶  然后点火
dumped in an oil drum, and set on fire.
道上的说法是  他在一场抢地盘的
Yeah, word on the street was that
争斗中  被一个毒贩杀了
a dealer killed him over a turf war.
为什么伯恩斯要关注他
So why was Burns looking at him?
银行把监控录像的片段发过来了
Yo. Bank just sent over surveillance footage.
你们得来看看这个
You guys gotta see this.
看上去他像在躲什么
Looks like he's running from something.
没错  看这个
He's running from something. All right. Watch this.
他知道他被拍到了
He knows he's on camera.
他想告诉我们些东西
He's trying to tell us something.
他写下来了
He's writing it.
倒回去看下
Okay, take it back.
在这停下
And freeze there.
他拿着刀
He's got a knife.
他试图给我们传递信息
He was trying to send us a message,
却录下了自己的被害的过程
but he recorded his own murder.
放大那张脸
Close up on the face.
卡塞尔  看那是谁
Castle, look at that face.
竟然是赫利·罗梅罗
That's Harley Romero.
而且他还活得好好的
And he is very much alive.
他为什么要停下来写这条讯息呢
Why would he stop to write a message?
为什么不继续跑呢
Why not just keep running?
那条街通向一个死胡同
Well, that street empties on to a blind alley.
或许伯恩斯觉得自己跑不了了
Maybe Burns thought he couldn't get away.
知道他写的是什么吗
Any idea what he was writing there?
要看技术部门能不能加强图像效果了
We're seeing if tech can enhance the image,
可我们还没发现
But we found no connection
赫利和披萨店的联系
between this Harley and the pizza joints.
如果两者本来就没关系呢
Maybe pizza has nothing to do with it.
伯恩斯可能从以前的报道中知道赫利的
Maybe Burns knew Harley from an old story.
不  我不认识这人
No. I-I don't recognize him at all.
伯恩斯有在他报道里
Did Burns ever mention the name Harley
提到赫利这名字吗
in any of his stories?
从没有过  这家伙诈死的时候
Never. When this guy supposedly died,
格顿在跟随海军二师
Gordon was embedded with the 2nd Marine Division
报道第二次海湾战争
in Gulf II.
肖恩先生  你知道强尼·法瑞尔
Mr. Shaw, do the names Johnny Farrell
或者斯维德·安德森有什么意思吗
or Swede Anderson mean anything to you?
当然
Yeah. They do.
他们都是老式好莱坞犯罪片里的角色
They're both characters from old film noir movies.
对了  强尼·法瑞尔是《吉尔达》里
Right. Uh, Johnny Farrell from the movie "Gilda,"
格伦·福特扮演的角色  伯特·兰卡斯特扮演
Glenn Ford's character, and Burt Lancaster played
《杀手》里的斯维德·安德森
Swede Anderson in "The Killers."
这两个名字有什么特殊之处吗
And why would these two names be important?
赫利这家伙买卖的是哪种毒品
This guy--Harley--what kind of drugs was he dealing?
海洛因  怎么了
Heroin, why?
伯恩斯追踪过的唯一一个海洛因报道
Because the only heroin story Burns ever chased
是他一直没能完成的那篇
was the one that he could never finish.
关于纽约高端贩毒圈里
About a high-end distribution ring in New York
用合法生意掩护海洛因交易
that sets up shop inside legitimate businesses.
有人需要购买时  就用密码进行交易
When someone needed product, they'd use a code word.
而那些密码就来自于老电影里的角色名
Their code happens to be names of characters from film noir.
就是这个故事毁了他
It's that story that destroyed him.
-怎么说  -那个在后台操控交易的人
- Why? - Because of the guy who was behind the ring.
是卡瓦罗
It was Cavallo.
格顿·伯恩斯惹到了黑暗王子本尊
Gordon Burns was gunning for the Prince of Darkness himself.
卡瓦罗是谁
Who's Cavallo?
只是一个街头神话  都市传说罢了
It's a-a street myth, an urban legend.
每当有毒贩子被杀
Anytime a dealer gets whacked,
人们都说是卡瓦罗干的
people always say it's Cavallo,
但这个人物根本不存在
but he's not even real.
有卡瓦罗这号人物
Oh, Cavallo's real.
算了吧  肖恩
Come on, Shaw.
这类的惊悚故事我们都听过
We've all heard the scary stories.
我没听过
I didn't.
据说卡瓦罗曾跟着无恶不作且有
So the story goes that Cavallo was mentored
"征服者"之称的哥伦比亚大毒枭
by this badass Colombian drug lord--
卡赞混过
Khazi "The conqueror"--
最后他用枪打爆了老板的头
and eventually he put a bullet to his boss' head,
割断了老板所有孩子的喉咙
slit all of his kids' throats,
然后抢班夺权
and took over the operation.
但这一切都只是个传说
But I mean, it's a fairy tale.
对伯恩斯来说不是
Not to Burns.
对他女儿也不是
Not to his daughter.
伯恩斯曾跟我说过他有门路
Burns told me he had a contact
能接近卡瓦罗
that was getting him close to Cavallo.
第二天  他和女儿
The next day, he and his daughter
正过马路的时候
are crossing the street,
一辆车突然冲出来
this car appears out of nowhere.
当他反应过来的时候
When he came to,
腿已经被撞得粉碎
his leg was shattered.
尼娜被撞飞20英尺远  流血不止
Nina was 20 feet away, bleeding out,
他想过去抱住她  却爬都爬不过去
and he couldn't even crawl over to hold her,
所以别再说卡瓦罗不存在
so don't you tell me Cavallo isn't real.
听起来伯恩斯像是阿哈
It sounds like Burns was Ahab,
卡瓦罗是白鲸
and Cavallo was white whale.
他还用梅尔维尔这个名字登入酒店呢
Well, he did sign in to the hotel as Melville.
伯恩斯就是靠这种诡秘的幽默感出名的
You know, it's that kind of sly humor that Burns was known for.
尽管我不喜欢侧写
And while I am loathe to profile,
卡瓦罗这个名字
the name Cavallo--
在意大利语中有"海洛因"的意思
also the Italian word for "Horse"--
暗示了这和四家尼克披萨店有某种联系
might suggest a link back to the four Nick's.
莱恩  你在缉毒组的时候
Hey, Ryan. When you were in narcotics,
第一次听到卡瓦罗这个名字是什么时候
when was the first time you heard the name Cavallo?
记不清了  大概是03年左右吧
I don't know. Probably around, uh, '03.
那个时候很多毒贩都被杀了
Around all that time all those dealers were getting whacked.
对  赫利也是那时候被杀的
Well, that's right when Harley was killed.
那么赫利伪装了自己的死亡
So Harley stages his own death,
残忍地杀害了竞争对手
brutally murders his competition,
然后又散播小道消息说
and then starts a whisper campaign on the streets
新的黑暗王子出现了
about the new Dark Prince of Heroin...
一个传说就这样诞生了
And a legend is born.
技术人员把自动取款机的录像放大了
Tech was able to blow up
并且加强了清晰度
and enhance that ATM video.
录像正在传输
They're sending it up now.
还是看不清楚写的什么
I still can't make it out.
再放一遍
Run it again.
能把这个图像翻转一下  再慢点放吗
Can you flip it and slow it down?
-可以  -你要干嘛
- Yeah. - What are you doing?
我最擅长的  写字
What I do best--writing.
好  3
Okay, 3...
6  s
6... s...
-也能是5  -好吧  s或5
- That could be a 5. - Okay, s or a 5...
W-1-2  7
W-1-2... 7?
是个地址
It's an address.
B  a  s
B... a... s?
地下室
Basement.
西127号街365号的地下室
365 west 127th street, in the basement.
那离自动取款机只有3个街区
That's three blocks from the ATM.
警察  都不许动
Police! Nobody move!
纽约警局
NYPD!
屋内安全
Room's clear.
人是匆匆撤离的
Somebody moved out in a hurry.
咖啡研磨机用来切东西
Coffee grinders for cutting.
信封用来装东西
Envelopes for packaging.
一切迹象都表明这是个井井有条的
All the earmarks of a well-organized
海洛因加工坊
heroin processing house.
叫鉴证组来  收集这里的证据
Get C.S.U. in here. Sweep the area.
有任何线索都要通知我
If anyone saw anything, I want to know.
看来阿哈找到他的白鲸了
Looks like your Ahab found his white whale.
还把他拉下了水
And it took him under.
老爸好  老爸再见
Hi, dad. Bye, dad.
都不亲我一下就走了
What, no kiss?
-阿丽克西斯  你脸怎么了  -没什么
- Alexis, what happened to your face? - Nothing.
这还叫没事  发生什么事了
That's not nothing. What happened?
是劳伦干的
Lauren.
她把我堵在学校的厕所里
She cornered me in the bathrooms at school,
说我毁了她的派对
said I ruined her party,
还说我黑了她的账号
and then she accused me of hacking into her account
删了她照的那些照片
and deleting those pictures she took.
说的像真的似的
As if.
然后怎么了
And--and then what happened?
我说她在我背后捅刀子
Well, I called her a backstabber,
她就抓了我的脸  于是我
and then she scratched me, so I...
-你干什么了  -我给了她一拳
- You what? - I punched her.
你当时怎么想的啊
Ah. What were you thinking?
我不知道  我从来不会这样
I don't know. This isn't me.
我不会擅闯别人的派对
I don't crash parties.
也不会跟别人打架
I don't get in fights with people.
但是  爸爸  她真的让我怒火中烧
I... But, dad, she made me so angry.
我知道  但是报复解决不了问题
I know she did, but retaliation is not the answer.
你报复她一次  她回击你一次
You get her back, she gets you back,
然后说不准哪天
and then one day,
你俩中的一个就死在披萨烤箱里了
one of you ends up dead in a pizza oven.
这是你想要的吗  关键是
Is that what you want? Look, the point is,
你一生中可能会跟很多这种卑鄙的
you're gonna have to deal with mean, backstabbing girls
背后伤人的女孩打交道
your whole life.
要学得精明一些  不受这些事的影响
You need to learn to be smart enough to rise above.
好吗
Okay?
好吧
Okay.
过来
Come here.
你痛扁她了吗
Did you kick her ass?
差不多
I kinda did.
好样的
Good girl.
我应该早点干涉这件事的
I should've gotten involved much earlier.
为什么  劳伦还是会找机会
Why? Lauren would've still found a way
让阿丽克西斯苦不堪言的
to make Alexis' life miserable.
劳伦又不是犯罪老手
Lauren isn't a criminal mastermind.
-她不过是个青少年  -卡塞尔
- She's just a teenager. - Ah, Castle,
永远不要低估肩负使命的女人的力量
never underestimate the power of a woman on a mission.
不会的  我的赡养费支票证明了这一点
No, I don't. And I have the alimony checks to prove it.
贝克特  我刚跟实验室那边通完电话
Beckett, just hung up with the lab.
海洛因加工坊发现的毒品残留
That trace heroin from the processing house?
与下东区兜售的毒品相匹配
It matches most of the dope being peddled on the Lower East.
有赫利的线索吗
Any word on this Harley?
长官  如果关于这家伙的传言有一半是真的
Sir, if half of the rumors about this guy are true,
那么他的眼线到处都是
then he's got snitches all over the force,
所以我想等有足够的证据再全面通缉他
so I was thinking of holding off on an A.P.B. until we knew more.
-随时向我汇报  -遵命
- Keep me posted. - Yes, sir.
肖恩说过卡瓦罗
You know, Shaw said that Cavallo
在利用很多正当业务销售毒品
is using legitimate businesses to distribute product.
你觉得他有没有可能就操控着
You think he could be operating
尼克披萨店中的一家
out of one of the Nicks'?
可能  这种无根据的调查我是拿不到搜查令的
Yeah, but I can't get a warrant for a fishing expedition.
我们需要掌握更确凿的证据
We're gonna have to have something more concrete.
鉴证组把那个地下室搜了个底朝天
C.S.U. swept the tenement basement top to bottom,
连个指纹也没找到
there's not one print anywhere.
有目击者看见伯恩斯被追杀了吗
Any witnesses see Burns getting chased?
在那片街区  看见了也没人说的
In that neighborhood, nobody sees nothing.
不过我们有一位警员
But one of our uniforms
在自动取款机附近的下水道里发现了这个
did find this in a storm drain near the ATM.
伯恩斯的手机
Burns' phone?
你们不觉得奇怪吗
Does it strike anyone else as strange
一个经验丰富的战地记者
that a seasoned war correspondent
会突然变得笨手笨脚
would suddenly develop butterfingers,
被追的时候掉了手机吗
drop his phone while being chased?
你认为他是故意的
You think he purposefully dropped it?
这样追他的的人就拿不到他的手机
So that whoever was chasing him wouldn't get his phone?
或是他手机上的东西
Or what was on it.
他最后打的电话是911
The last call he made was 9-1-1
但是他没有打出去
and he didn't press send.
毒品加工坊的外面
Outside the drug lab.
他在蹲点
He was casing the joint.
那是莫妮卡  她也参与其中
That's Monica. She's involved.
莫妮卡·怀特  纽约警局  开门
Monica Wyatt, NYPD! Open up!
莫妮卡
Monica!
退后
Step back.
纽约警局
NYPD!
莫妮卡
Monica.
他想杀我
He...he tried to kill me.
窗户
Window.
走
Let's go.
莫妮卡  是谁干的
Monica, who did this to you?
要是我告诉了你  我就死定了
If I tell you, then I'm dead.
现在这种情形就别隐瞒了  谁干的
I think we're past that. Who did it?
卡瓦罗
Cavallo.
之前关于格顿我没有说谎
I wasn't lying before about Gordon.
我们几年前是约会过  我以为那是认真的
We did date years ago, and I thought it was real,
但他那么做只是为了接近卡瓦罗
but he was just doing it to get close to Cavallo.
我从没想过
I never imagined that...
一个市中心房地产经纪人
What's a midtown real estate agent
怎么会和毒贩牵扯到一起
doing mixed up with heroin dealers?
他们的作坊地点经常更换
Their labs are mobile.
他们的加工中心
They need new places
每个月都要换新地点
for their processing centers every month or so,
而我有他们所需要的信息
and I had access to all the information that they needed.
听着  我不是这样的
Look... This is not who I am.
我是说  我从没想到...
I mean, I never meant for anything...
你是怎么开始的
How did it start?
几年前我有些麻烦
I had some problems a few years back.
我欠了一些人钱
I owed some people money.
一个男人找到我
A man came to me
告诉我他可以解决我的问题
and he told me that he could make it all better.
我只要  时不时的帮他们点小忙
I just... Had to do a favor for him every now and then.
那时候听上去没什么坏处
And at the time, that actually sounded harmless.
但是这个男人知道我的事情
But this man knew things about me.
我是说那些没人可能知道的事情
I mean things that nobody could possibly know.
我想过离开
And I wanted to leave,
但是  格顿孩子出事之后  我就
but... after what happened to Gordon's kid, I just...
格顿几天前找到了我
Gordon found me a couple of days ago.
他说他需要我的帮助
He said he needed my help.
他说我可以结束这一切
He said that I could end this,
然后我们都可以自由了
and that we both could be free.
我只要把他带到那里
All I had to do was take him there.
现在格顿死了
And now Gordon is dead,
我就是下一个
and I am next.
卡瓦罗是谁
Cavallo--who is he?
我从来没见过他
I've never seen him.
他刚刚不是试图想杀你吗
Didn't he just try to kill you?
如果我知道卡瓦罗是谁
If I knew who Cavallo was,
我早就告诉格顿了
don't you think I would've told Gordon?
我只和卡瓦罗的副手接触过
I've only ever dealt with Cavallo's right-hand man before.
是他想要杀我
That's who was here trying to kill me.
这个人是谁
And who is this man?
他的名字是赫利
His name is Harley.
他吗
Him?
赫利就是卡瓦罗
Harley is Cavallo.
这么说卡瓦罗就躲在我们的眼皮底下
So Cavallo is hiding right under everyone's noses.
-我怎样才能找到他  -都是他来找我
- How do I find him? - He finds me.
莫妮卡  格顿说的对
Monica, Gordon was right.
我们可以结束这一切  但是我们需要你的帮助
We can end this, but we need your help.
我们认为卡瓦罗通过一个披萨店
We believe that Cavallo is trafficking drugs
来贩运毒品
through a pizzeria,
但我们得知道是哪一个
but we need to know which one.
对不起  我不知道是哪一个
I'm sorry. I don't know which one.
我们找了整个区域
We covered the whole area.
不管是谁  都让他逃走了
Whoever he was, he's in the wind.
好吧  不如你们把莫妮卡送到急诊室
All right. Why don't you guys take Monica to the E.R. ?
给她做检查  然后把她送到缉毒组
Get her checked, and then get her over to Narcotics.
让他们和她谈谈
Let them talk to her.
最后一个问题
One last question
强尼·法瑞尔和斯维德·安德森
Johnny Farrell and Swede Anderson?
这是格顿跟进这件事的原因
That's how Gordon got on to this story in the first place.
他在披萨店里听到有人在用这几个名字
He heard somebody at one of the pizza joints using those names,
他知道这是卡瓦罗的暗号
and he knew it was Cavallo's code.
那些是上个星期的名字
Those were last week's names.
你知道这个星期的名字吗
Do you know this week's names?
不知道  但是格顿说名字出自他最喜欢的电影
No, but Gordon said they were from his favorite film
《马耳他之鹰》
"The Maltese Falcon."
-你就是个小偷  -什么  我是什么
- You're a sneak. - What? I'm a what?
我不在乎这些人会不会认出你
I don't care if these guys could've recognized you.
要是再把他们留在这儿
You hold 'em much longer,
这里马上就会有另一起谋杀案了
there's gonna be another murder on our hands.
放轻松  我们马上就好了
Relax. We're almost done.
我们已经查了两家  还有两家
We got two Nicks down, two to go.
好吧  一会再打给你
Okay. Call you in a bit.
我在想我们是不是应该用
I wonder if I should've used
悉尼·格林斯特里特  英国著名演员
卡斯帕·古特曼则是他在《马耳他之鹰》里扮演的角色
悉尼·格林斯特里特的角色  卡斯帕·古特曼
Sydney Greenstreet's character-- Kasper Gutman.
他才是个喜欢披萨的人
Now there's a guy who loved his pizza.
我们都已经赌鲍嘉了
Well, we already put our money down on Bogie,
我们就继续演下去吧
So let's just play this through.
一片披萨吗
Slice?
不  是给斯佩德的外卖
Uh, no, a pickup actually for Spade--
萨姆·斯佩德
Sam Spade.
当然  斯佩德先生
Of course, Mr. Spade.
你的货就在我们这里
We have your order right here.
给你  斯佩德先生
Here you go, Mr. Spade.
我们会记你账上的
We put it on your tab.
谢谢
Thank you.
赢家  今晚披萨晚餐
Winner, Winner, Pizza Dinner.
藏毒  运毒  预谋贩毒
Possession, trafficking, conspiracy to distribute--
这些就可以轻松判你30年  萨尔
that right there is 30 years, easy, Sal--
"美味正宗"的30年
30 Terrific Authentic years.
如果你是伯恩斯谋杀案的从犯那就是终身监禁
It's life if you're an accessory to Burns' murder.
不  我发誓我和那一点关系都没有
No, I had nothing to do with that. I swear.
你发誓  那么你想告诉我们什么
You swear? So what are you trying to tell me?
你想告诉我们
Are you trying to tell me
是赫利想到把尸体放进你对手的烤箱
that Harley had the idea to put the body in your rival's oven?
你是做披萨的  萨尔
You're a pizza man, Sal.
把尸体放进烤箱听上去更像是你的主意
Body in an oven sounds more like you're speed.
不  不是的  是他  这全是他干的
No. No, no, no, it was him. It was all him.
怎么  现在你是个被害人了吗
So what, now you're a victim?
听着  我的店生意惨淡
Look, my place was struggling.
他找到我说  他的老板可以帮我
He came to me, he said the man that he worked for could help.
我只要把我的店给他们用几个月
All I had to do was let him use my shop for a couple of months,
然后他就可以
then he would make...
让我的梦想成真
my dream come true.
你的梦想
Your dream?
是的  他说  等一切都结束了
Yeah, he said, uh, after it was over,
他的老板会
the man he worked for would, uh...
会把正宗尼克披萨店给烧了
burn down Authentic Nick's.
毒品不是我的风格
This ain't me.
我连大麻都没抽过
I never even smoked a joint.
但是那些尼克们  他们做的那些事
But all those other Nicks, the stuff they were doing,
都快把我逼疯了
it was driving me crazy.
伯恩斯的尸体是怎么到烤箱里去的
How did Burns' body get in the oven?
那天晚上赫利打电话给我
Harley called me that night,
说他要在我的烤箱里放点东西过夜
said he needed to throw something in my oven overnight.
他没说是什么
He didn't say what it was.
但你知道那不会是一盘意式千层面
Yeah, but you knew it wasn't a tray of lasagna.
我也说了不行
And I said no way.
不可能的  我从没答应过提供火葬服务
No way. I never signed up for cremation services.
我完全没想到我拒绝的东西
I never dreamed what I turned away
会出现在拉尔夫·卡波的烤箱里
would end up in Ralph Carbone's oven.
想要我们帮你吗  萨尔
You want our help, Sal?
想让我在检察官那儿替你求情吗
You want me to put in a good word with the D.A.?
-想  -那就帮我找他
- Yeah.  - Then help me find him.
帮我找到卡瓦罗
Help me find Cavallo.
你没法找他
You can't find him.
只能等他来找你
He finds you.
那可不是在帮我  萨尔
That's not helping me, Sal.
你没明白
You don't get it.
当我没货时就打电话给他
When I run out of product, I call him.
他会送来
He delivers.
那就打给他
Make the call.
赫利·罗梅罗  即传说中的卡瓦罗
Harley Romero, A.K.A, the legendary Cavallo.
律师不来他不开口
He won't talk without a lawyer.
有自动取款机的监控录像
With the evidence from the ATM video
和萨尔的证词  他是得要个律师
and Sal's testimony, he's gonna need one.
想一想  这真是太绝了
You know, it's brilliant when you think about it.
在所有人都在忙着
The innocent middleman does all the dirty work
寻找传说中的邪恶领主时
while everyone stays busy
无辜的中间人已干完所有勾当
looking for the menacing mythic overlord...
却从来没人见过他  因为他是虚构的
Who no one ever meets because he's not really real.
无论虚实
Well, real or not,
他逍遥法外时间太久了  干得好
he's going away for a lot time. Good work.
缉毒组已经问完莫妮卡·怀特
Narcotics is finished with Monica Wyatt.
-她很配合  -好  办完手续让她走
- She cooperated fully. - Okay, process her out.
这几个晚上在她家外面派辆巡逻车
And put a patrol car outside her building
以防卡瓦罗有同党
for the next few nights, just in case Cavallo has friends.
怎么了
What's up?
我只是在想伯恩斯  想到他距离逮到杀害
I was just thinking about Burns, how close he came to catching
她女儿的凶手仅一步之遥  却没能成功
the guy who killed his daughter only to come up short.
如果有什么慰藉的话  至少现在正义得以伸张
Well, if it's any consolation, there's justice now.
-知道我有什么地方想不通吗  -什么
- Yeah, you know what's still bug in me? - Hmm?
他在逃命
The guy is runnining for his life,
为什么还要丢掉手机
why does he ditch his s one?
他可能知道自己会被杀
Well he probably knew that he was gonna get killed,
所以希望至少有人能知道真相
and he wanted at least someone to know the truth.
什么真相
What truth?
里面又没有卡瓦罗的照片
It wasn't like there was a picture of Cavallo on it.
你说的对
No, you're right.
手机里唯一一张照片就是...
The only person he had a picture of was...
还有几个问题  怀特女士
just a few more questions, Ms. Wyatt.
我等一个多小时了
I have been waiting over an hour.
这起案件最有趣的地方就是
You know the funny thing about this case is that
每个人都名不副实  包括你
nobody is who they claim to be, not even you.
莫妮卡·怀特  这里说
Monica Wyatt--it says here
2002年  你从洛杉矶搬到纽约
You moved to New York in 2002 from L.A.
是啊  所以呢
Yeah, so?
所以我们查了一下
So we did a little bit of digging,
找到的唯一一个莫妮卡·怀特
And the only Monica Wyatt that we found
是一个被近距离枪杀后
was a heroin addict who was shot point-blank
扔到洛杉矶大河的瘾君子
and then dumped in the L.A. River.
六个月后
Six months later,
道上盛传一位新任的残暴的毒枭出现了
word of a new and brutal kingpin started sweeping the streets.
你是说那人是我吗
And you're saying that's me?
我是个地产经纪人  你们不是见过我家吗
I'm a real estate agent. Have you seen my apartment?
是啊  见过你的
Oh, yeah, we saw that one.
但其它的房子  只能在网上看房
But all of the other ones can only be previewed online.
你是在说什么
What are you talking about?
你的买家华特·尼夫  弗兰克·钱伯斯
Your apartment sales to Walter Neff, Frank Chambers,
理查德·哈兰德全是黑色电影里的角色
Richard harland--they're all characters from noir films.
都是虚构的
They aren't real.
你把上千万毒资
You made millions in heroin holdings,
都转化成了房地产投资
which you turned into millions in real estate holdings,
洗得一干二净
All clean.
而且你还一直
All the while,
延续着卡瓦罗的罪恶传说
perpetuating the myth of Cavallo.
格顿不是死于追查传说
Gordon didn't die chasing a myth.
对了  格顿
Oh, yeah, Gordon.
你倒是没全撒谎
Well, there's something that you didn't completely lie about.
你们确实是几年前认识的
You did meet him a couple of years ago,
但他不是你的男友
but not as a boyfriend.
而是个知道得太多
He was a pain-in-the-ass reporter
令人讨厌的记者
that just kept getting a little too close.
直到无端端冲出一辆车  撞死了他的女儿
Until a car came out of nowhere and killed his daughter.
这才使他好多年都没再纠缠你
That got him out of your hair for a couple of years,
但后来他在披萨店又察觉到了你的踪迹
but then he caught your scent again at Nick's Pizza.
这迫使你要斩草除根
And that forced you to get rid of him permanently.
于是你就供出赫利  作为替罪羊
And then you fed us Harley, the sacrificial lamb,
以转移我们的注意力
to throw us off your trail.
赫利攻击了我
Harley attacked me.
是啊  然后他从消防梯跑了
Oh, yeah, and then he managed to run down the fire escape
快的难以置信
with such incredible speed
两位全纽约最棒的警探
that two of New York's finest detectives
连他影都没见着  抓他就更别想了
were incapable of seeing him, never mind catching him.
苦肉计
Beating yourself up...
这招不错
was a nice touch.
我刚刚才意识到
You know what I just realized
所有卡瓦罗挑选名字的那些电影
all those noir films that Cavallo draws his names from,
皆有一个共同点
they all have one thing in common--
都有个蛇蝎美人
a femme fatale.
我现在要请律师
I'd like my lawyer now.
啊  太好了
Ah, great.
你还没睡
You're still up.
想睡也睡不着
Couldn't sleep if I wanted to.
我也是
That makes two of us.
-是从斯特凡诺店买的吗  -当然
- Is that from Stefano's?  - Mm-hmm.
为了买个披萨你大老远跑到桥那边去吗
You went all the way across the bridge for a pizza?
这不是为了我乖女儿嘛
Not for just anyone.
新鲜的罗勒和香肠
Fresh basil and sausage.
那事怎么样了
Any updates on, uh...
我今天请了
Uh, um... I called a mediation session
学校辅导员来调解
with our school counselor today.
结果劳伦就是嫉妒
And it turns out, Lauren was just jealous of
我整天跟阿什利在一起
all the time I was spending with ashley.
她觉得我重色轻友
She thought I had ditched our friendship.
那你怎么办
So what'd you do?
我们尽释前嫌
We hugged it out.
那现在又是朋友了吗
And now you're friends again?
言之尚早
It's too soon to tell.
这类伤痛
Hurts like these...
需要时间来愈合
take time to heal.
时间
Time...
和披萨
and pizza.
噢  瞧呀
Ohh. Ooh, look at that.
干披萨
Cheers.